Jack: To make sure that we are
communicating correctly we need
to first seek feedback and not
just expect it to come to us.
The first thing to think about
when seeking feedback is what
do we want from the feedback?
Is it to know whether the communication
was understood, was clear to everyone?
Or to be more specific, such as
getting individuals to feedback
directly with data and immediate
responses to particular questions.
The things that we most commonly
seek feedback about are suitability,
relevancy, and usefulness.
We want to see if the message we were
trying to get across was received by all
and was clear, effective, and informative.
Leah: So, who do we
seek that feedback from?
Within a programming environment the
other parties that we may seek feedback
from are clients with whom we may be
communicating about their new software,
colleagues, and team members who we may
be collaborating with on a development
project, and managers, stakeholders,
and any third parties who may be
involved at some stage with a project.
It doesn’t matter who they are,
their feedback will often help
with the process of communication.
Jack: So how can we get feedback that
meets our requirements and is timely?
The person who is communicating should
set out the guidelines for feedback
and make sure that they ask for it.
They should also make everyone aware that
feedback is an important and helpful way
of them confirming their understanding
and in turn for gaining a response.
For a more
Leah: efficient process they should
enable feedback to be given by means
of creating a mechanism for it.
Feedback can be given by a variety of
means such as by informal and formal
meetings, email questioning, polls,
surveys, focus groups and questionnaires.
The approach will depend on
the feedback that is wanted
and how quickly it is needed.